迈克 · 诺斯: 我们甚至可以定义我们自己的防守类型。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: We can even
define our own type guards.
Mike North: 这个叫做，这个叫做用户定义的类型保护。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So this is called, this is
referred to as a user defined type guard.
如果我们看一下这里的实现，这个返回的类型是什么？
And if we look at the implementation here,
what type does this return?
这是什么类型的？
What's this type here?
类型等于字符串。
Type of something equals string.
迈克 · 诺斯: 这是一个布尔值，对吗？
&gt;&gt; Mike North: It's a Boolean, right?
类型，如果我们要捕获这个值，它是一个布尔值。
Type of, if we were to capture that value,
it's a Boolean.
一个布尔值以另一个布尔值结束，它会给我们一个布尔值。
And a Boolean ended with another Boolean,
it's gonna give us a Boolean.
所以这里的返回值，我们肯定是返回一个布尔值。
So the return here,
we're definitely returning a Boolean.
但是我们已经向打字稿编译器表明它应该
But we have indicated to
the typescript compiler that it should
将此布尔值的 true 或 false 作为指示
regard the true or false value
of this Boolean as an indication
X 的类型是否有电子邮件。
of whether x is of type has e-mail.
这样我们就可以使用它，就像我们使用
And that allows us down here to use
it just like we're using type of and
在前面的例子中。
instance of in the previous examples.
我们可以使用它将未知的范围缩小到有电子邮件的范围。
We can use it to narrow from
an unknown down to a has e-mail.
这些是超级，超级方便，对不对？
These are super, super handy, right?
这是你自己的定制类型，你有在你的应用程序,
This is where your own custom
types that you have in your app,
你可以创造好的警卫，让你处理特定的案件。
you can create nice guards that will
allow you to handle specific cases.
这是我最喜欢的警卫，我到处都用它。
This is my favorite guard,
I use it all over the place.
定义。
Is defined.
我们把仿制药带回到这里。
And we're bringing back generics here.
以下是原因。
Here's why.
我们有一个紧密的参数 t。
We have a tight parameter T.
我们取一个参数，可以是 t 或
We take an argument, which could be T or
我们返回 arg 是否是 t。
undefined, and
we return whether the arg is T.
所以我们试图排除它未定义的可能性。
So we're trying to remove
the possibility that it is undefined.
如果我们看一下这里的返回值，就会得到正确的布尔值
And if we look at the return here, that is
gonna give us the correct Boolean value
如果我们想知道这是一个未定义的值。
if we're trying to figure out that
this is a non-undefined value.
它的价值是被定义的。
It's value is defined.
我这样做的原因是因为如果我通过了
The reason I do things this way
is because if I were to pass
这个值可以是字符串，但也可以是未定义的,
this a value that could be a string but
could also be undefined,
当类型检查符合的时候，就像这样。
when the type checking matches that up,
it's kind of like it does this.
迈克 · 诺斯: 它几乎是这样排列的。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: It almost
lines things up this way.
所以 t 变成了弦。
And so, T becomes string.
所以这就是我如何能够提取出未定义的。
So this is how I'm able to kind
of pluck out the undefined.
我在《迈克 · 诺斯》中传递的观点是: 有吗
The argument I pass in
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Has it's
未定义值删除。
undefined value removed.
如果你有一个类似这样的东西的清单，这是非常有用的。
And this is useful if you have
a list of things, like this.
Mike North: 对，所以这是一个类型为 string 或 undefined 的数组。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Right, so this is
an array of type string or undefined.
清单。
List.
迈克 · 诺斯: 过滤器。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Filter.
麦克 · 诺斯: 过滤。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Filtered.
我们移除了所有未定义的值，并且
We've removed all of the undefined values,
and
我们也删除了未定义的类型。
we've removed undefined
from the type as well.
所以，如果你有一个收藏，并且
So it's great if you have a collection,
and
假设你有一个类型的可选值，你有一个它们的数组。
say you have some optional value on
a type, and you have an array of them.
您可以尝试将它们全部删除，过滤掉所有未定义的值。
You can just attempt to pluck all them
off, filter out all the undefined values.
事情就是这样。
Things just work.
我想知道他们是否修好了这个。
I wonder if they fixed this.
迈克 · 诺斯: 所以，实际上，我认为这正是它应该做的。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So this, actually, I think
this is doing exactly what it should be.
但事实上，字符串可以有一个虚假的值
But the fact that string
can have a falsey value
意味着一个空字符串作为 false 通过布尔构造函数。
means that an empty string passes through
the Boolean constructor as false.
这就是为什么我们不能真正区分空字符串和
Which is why we can't really tell the
difference between an empty string, and
一个布尔值。
a Boolean.
他们都会给出同样真实的检查。
They both will give the same
truthy-falsey check.
但实际上,
But it's really,
当与过滤函数结合使用时，定义了真正有用的。
really useful, is defined, when used in
conjunction with filtering functions.